Ashwin Ramesh

SOFTWARE TESTER



SUMMARY

Around 5 years of software testing experience with through knowledge of project & software life cycle methodologies. Single handedly worked in multiple agile projects which involved teams from both offshore and onshore. Developed and implemented numerous testing guidelines and principles which led to sucessful collaborative projects. An accomplished software tester with professionalism and enthusiasm.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Test Analyst Psiog Digital Private Limited

Nov 2020 - Present

- Experience in formulating test stratagies, developing test scripts and executing test cases.
- Involved in Mobile App Testing
- Well versed with different types of testing like Integration testing,
 Performance testing, Smoke testing and Regression testing
- Worked based on dead lines with multiple releases in a week.
- Tracked the bugs and maintained Test Artifacts using JIRA, Azure Devops.
- Attended Sprint Planning, Design reviews, daily meetings and to address any issues/blockers.
- Worked on delivering the Build and Release certificates on each releases.
- Had a flexibility to take over two projects individually and completing it sucessfully
- Presented PPT on QA's View of Agile and Software testing.
- Operated independently, reviewing results of QA projects.
- Well Recognized for excellent problem solving and analytical skills by Programmers, Project Managers and Supervisors.

Quality Analyst Cognizant Technology Solutions

Dec 2016 - Oct 2020

- Started testing carrier on working for an American Insurance Company.
- Worked on Kanban and Scrum teams.
- Writing and executing test plans, designing and developing test tools, debugging and reporting code bugs and pushing quality upstream.
- Worked closely with the Development team on a daily basis to ensure timely resolution of defects.
- Partnered with cross-functional teams to seek inputs on process improvements and improved re-use of test assets.
- Involved in Team Retro and PI planning events to provide testing inputs.
- Had experience in working on SOAP UI Rest API tools.
- Executed SQL queries and worked on database testing as well.

CONTACT

- ✓ ashwinramesh45@gmail.co
   m
- 9551334254
- Chennai, India
- in linkedin.cohttps://www.linke din.com/in/ashwin-ramesh-035972198/m/in/boris

SKILLS

Manual Testing

API Testing

Selenium

JIRA

UNIX

AZURE DEVOPS

DATABASE TESTING

Critical Thinking

Ability to Learn Quickly

SDLC and STLC

Flexibility

- Developed test scenarios for functional, regression and integration testing.
- Participated in the weekly bug status/review meeting with the Developers and Project Managers.
- Performed functional testing and automated web applications using Selenium web driver.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering in Electronics and Communication Engineering MNM Jain Engineering College, Chennai Aug 2011 - Apr 2015